### **Ryan White**

### Springfield, MO

(510) 853-6633 • wryan@chromium.org

## **OBJECTIVE**

Technology passionate and customer compassionate Systems/Network/Dev professional with a strong understanding of hardware, software, and data communication systems with a myriad of skills managing bare metal servers, network hardware, hypervisors, storage, code repos, and systems. Proven operations and administration experience on a vast number of platforms and system integrations with in physical, cloud, and virtual environments at scale.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Coin Cloud - Systems and DevOps Engineer — Las Vegas, NV --- GitHub https://github.com/ryanwhitecc

June 2022 — June 2023

SaaS Administrator - Google Workspace, Github, Atlassian Jira/Confluence, Heroku, Netlify. Namecheap (DNS).

<u>Linux Administrator</u> - Managed numerous crypto nodes and BitPay Wallet Service nodes. Amazon Linux EC2. 100's of Ubuntu ATM machines around the USA and 40+ in Brazil. Linux hardening.

<u>AWS cloud administrator</u> - Reduced AWS spend even as our fleet grew by more than 10x. Created AWS Cloudwatch alerts, monitoring and logging on AWS Budgets, EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, SQS, S3. Serverless framework. Some work with ECR and ECS. Reduced tech debt: removed dead code, old services, users. Rotated EC2 SSH keys.

<u>MongoDB</u> - Worked on performance tuning with my manger using indexes, reducing unnecessary data reads and writes. Fixed deprecated Mongoose code to reduce errors.

<u>DevOps engineer</u> - Implemented code scanning with Sonar Cloud and Github Actions pipelines. Terraform to create and manage infrastructure as code. Bash scripting, Javascript, NodeJs, Java, Sprint planning and refinement meetings for Web/Mobile. Cleaned up our code base, code translation and fixed code errors. Updated Lambda runtimes.

<u>Security improvements</u> - Increased security with hardware MFA devices, SSO, hid plaintext secrets. permissions improvements, and network ACLs. Implemented SAML Google SSO with AWS and Github. API PoC with MTLS. Added WAF, Security Hub, GuardDuty. Reduced attack surface, disabled root login/switching. Disabled Linux password authentication and set-up SSH keys.

### Astreya - NetOps Engineer @ Facebook — Remote

March 2020 — March 2022

Facebook production network, CDN, and Hyper-Scale computing, POP/Co-Lo Datacenter Environments

Facebook Network Appliance (FNA): Edge Networking with Global ISPs

System Admin CentOS - Woking with HPE on our POP G9/10 Proliant server fleet

Maintaining ISP rack switches (Arista/Cisco Nexus), BGP peering, and caching servers

Many process improvements and innovations. Improved cross-functional relationships with internal teams, external vendors, and managed service providers like Ericsson, Sycomp, and IBM.

Key member of a new Python tool development initiative.

# Google Contract - Lab Systems/Network/Automation — Mountain View/Sunnyvale, CA

November 2017 — March 2020

A core member of lab infrastructure teams involved in the planning and implementation of multiple labs. Collaborated with HwOps and NetOps folks to draft network topology, port-mapping, and BoM/MoP docs.

Worked with our Partner Integration team to set-up Hyper-Converged Infrastructure products from Dell and Cisco for testing and qualification.

Configured and managed numerous iSCSI SAN and NAS devices for dev teams. SNMP/Monitoring with Nagios, LibreNMS, Grafana, and Graylog.

Provisioned redundant networks in multiple labs with dual ToR switches, dual chassis/line-cards/supervisor routing using LACP, VPC, MLAG, and HSRP on Cisco IOS, Nexus NX-OS, and Arista platforms.

Deployed and managed Linux VMs (Ubuntu and CentOS) for network services (DHCP, NAT, DNS).

Set-up physical and virtual F5s for Kubernetes use (licensing, upgrades, mgmt, interfaces, VLAN, routes, Self IPs).

Spun-up bare metal/virtual compute clusters for Anthos that replicate customer premise environments utilizing internal Google and Dell servers, EMC storage, VMware ESXi/vCenter, Linux, Git, and Ansible in a infrastructure as code environment. Bash, expect, and python scripting.

Traveled with the roadshow team to deploy two complete system mock-ups featured onstage for the Google Next 2018 GKE On-Prem keynote/product unveiling which were also showcased offstage during customer breakout sessions.

# Systems Administrator/Support: Stanford University (OHS) — Stanford, CA

May 2016 — November 2018

Systems Administrator for web and cloud based systems and Stanford systems integrations. Provided technical support to staff, teachers, and remote students/families. Developed technology course content for onboarding and troubleshooting. Created a small A/V recording studio for course content.

## IT Support Specialist, California Public School System — South Bay, CA

December 2014 — April 2016

1:1 device program - Chromebooks, Android tablets, thin and zero clients, Windows Server, Mac, VMware.

VPN routers for County networking, WAN overhaul, network upgrades, A/V systems, smart whiteboards.

# **EDUCATION**

### Colorado State University: Global Campus — Aurora, CO

June 2021 - Bachelor's of Science, Information Technology, Magna Cum Laude

Advanced Networking Enterprise Systems with Windows Server 2016 (70-740, 70-741)

Intermediate Linux Networking (Linux+), Ethical Hacking, MySQL Database Administration, Python Programming

IT Project Management, Accounting, Leadership Principles, Business Communication

#### Foothill College — Los Altos Hills, CA & San Jose City College — San Jose, CA

October 2017 - Associate of Science, Computer Science

CCNP: Routing, Switching, Troubleshooting, CCNA: Scaling Networks/Connecting

Machine, Assembly, C, C++, Java & Python Programming, Linux CLI and Shell Scripting

Network+/Security+, Windows Server 2008 and Microsoft Active Directory Administration

### Nucamp Coding Bootcamp — Remote online --- GitHub https://github.com/ryan-white2

June 2022 - Back End, SQL, and DevOps with Python

Python data structures, algorithms. PostgresSQL, SQLAlchemy, Docker, Flask, Django, Alembic

Amazon AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud, SLDC, CI/CD, DevOps

August 2023 – Full Stack Web and Mobile Development

Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, Express, React Native, Google Cloud, Firebase, MongoDB.

**CERTIFICATIONS:** https://github.com/ryan-white2/resume